<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-08T22:29:32+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Everything’s swirling</title><subtitle>It&apos;s what I am.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My 2023 in film</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2024/01/07/my-2023-in-film/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My 2023 in film" /><published>2024-01-07T13:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-07T13:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2024/01/07/my-2023-in-film</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2024/01/07/my-2023-in-film/">&lt;figure class=&quot;figure w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53448751619_65cc69cc68_b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-image img-fluid rounded mx-auto w-100&quot; alt=&quot;My 2023 in film&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grange85/53448751619/in/dateposted/&quot;&gt;My 2024 in film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I watched 340 films&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average score of the films I watched was 5.84 / 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I saw 6.6% of them on the big screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;52% of the films I watched were from before I was born&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;21 were animated, 3 were westerns and 15 were musicals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;93.2% of films were in English&lt;br /&gt;
other langugaes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Arabic (1)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bengali (5)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Czech (1)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;German (2)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;French (7)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Japanese (4)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Swedish (1)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;silent (6)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the films I rated 10 were old favourites!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ice Cold in Alex (1958)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Matter of Life and Death (1946)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Maltese Falcon (1941)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Lady Vanishes (1938)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweet Charity (1969)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest rated films I hadn’t seen before all scored 9s and included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anatomy of a Fall (2023)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;City Lights (1931) &lt;em&gt;although I suspect I had seen this before a long, long time ago&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFvHep5vaCQ&quot;&gt;Never Be a Punching Bag for Nobody&lt;/a&gt; (2023)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/swirling/2023/01/04/my-year-in-film-2022/&quot;&gt;My 2022 in film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/swirling/2021/02/15/my-2020-in-film/&quot;&gt;My 2020 in film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/swirling/2018/01/20/films-rated-2017/&quot;&gt;My 2017 in film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/swirling/2016/01/02/films-i-watched-in-2015/&quot;&gt;My 2015 in film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="film" /><category term="stats" /><summary type="html">My 2024 in film Stats I watched 340 films The average score of the films I watched was 5.84 / 10 I saw 6.6% of them on the big screen 52% of the films I watched were from before I was born 21 were animated, 3 were westerns and 15 were musicals 93.2% of films were in English other langugaes: Arabic (1) Bengali (5) Czech (1) German (2) French (7) Japanese (4) Swedish (1) silent (6) All the films I rated 10 were old favourites! Ice Cold in Alex (1958) A Matter of Life and Death (1946) The Maltese Falcon (1941) The Lady Vanishes (1938) Sweet Charity (1969) The highest rated films I hadn’t seen before all scored 9s and included: Anatomy of a Fall (2023) City Lights (1931) although I suspect I had seen this before a long, long time ago Never Be a Punching Bag for Nobody (2023) My 2022 in film My 2020 in film My 2017 in film My 2015 in film</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thomas the Rhymer</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/16/thomas-the-rhymer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thomas the Rhymer" /><published>2023-11-16T18:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T18:11:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/16/thomas-the-rhymer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/16/thomas-the-rhymer/">&lt;p&gt;Two facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hazel has family who live in Melrose, so we have visited and stayed in the town many times over the years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steeleye Span’s &lt;em&gt;Now We Are Six&lt;/em&gt; has been a favourite Span album of mine for many years (pre-dating my metal and indie phases), and Thomas the Rhymer is the best track on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53336151676_0ff526373e_c.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-image img-fluid rounded mx-auto&quot; alt=&quot;The Rhymer&apos;s Stone, Melrose&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-right&quot;&gt;The Rhymer&apos;s Stone, Melrose&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until earlier this year those facts were, in my mind, completely unrelated. Then I learned that the &lt;em&gt;Huntley Bank&lt;/em&gt; on which &lt;em&gt;True&lt;/em&gt; Thomas encountered &lt;em&gt;a lady gay&lt;/em&gt; was in Melrose. And the tree under which he sat that fateful day when he met the Queen of the Fairies has been commemorated by a stone erected by the &lt;em&gt;Melrose Literary Society&lt;/em&gt; in 1929.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, since we were visiting Hazel’s family we also visited the site of Thomas the Rhymer’s encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure w-100&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ox2jJX68e8Q&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/Ox2jJX68e8Q/maxres1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid opacity-3h4 mx-auto&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-right&quot;&gt;
        Steeleye Span - Thomas the Rhymer (play on YouTube)
      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html">Two facts: Hazel has family who live in Melrose, so we have visited and stayed in the town many times over the years. Steeleye Span’s Now We Are Six has been a favourite Span album of mine for many years (pre-dating my metal and indie phases), and Thomas the Rhymer is the best track on it. The Rhymer&apos;s Stone, Melrose Until earlier this year those facts were, in my mind, completely unrelated. Then I learned that the Huntley Bank on which True Thomas encountered a lady gay was in Melrose. And the tree under which he sat that fateful day when he met the Queen of the Fairies has been commemorated by a stone erected by the Melrose Literary Society in 1929. So today, since we were visiting Hazel’s family we also visited the site of Thomas the Rhymer’s encounter. Steeleye Span - Thomas the Rhymer (play on YouTube)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My October 2023 in film</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/04/my-october-in-film/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My October 2023 in film" /><published>2023-11-04T16:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-04T16:11:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/04/my-october-in-film</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/11/04/my-october-in-film/">&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/images/my-october-2023-in-film.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My October in Film&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shockingly nothing on the big screen, everything in English, and all talkies this month! But, a higher percentage than usual of films I haven’t rated (mostly haven’t &lt;em&gt;seen&lt;/em&gt;) before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Films watched: 20&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rated before: 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average score: 5.75/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the big screen: 0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Silent films: 0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non English language films: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films-watched-by-decade&quot;&gt;Films watched by decade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1920s: 1 (watched) / 8.00 (average rating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1930s: 1 (watched) / 7.00 (average rating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1940s: 2 / 5.50&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1950s: 1 / 8.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1960s: 3 / 5.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1970s: 4 / 5.50&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1980s: 1 / 6.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1990s: 2 / 6.50&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2000s: 3 / 4.67&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2010s: 0 / n/a&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2020s: 3 / 6.33&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;highest-rated-films&quot;&gt;Highest rated films&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alien (Ridley Scott, 1979)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sapphire (Basil Dearden, 1959)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="film" /><summary type="html">Quick summary and stats about the films I watched in October 2023. Shockingly nothing on the big screen, everything in English, and all talkies this month! #Music #Cinema #Film</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">American Analog Set - Trespassers in the stereo field website</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/10/29/american-analog-set-trespassers-in-the-stereo-field-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="American Analog Set - Trespassers in the stereo field website" /><published>2023-10-29T09:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-29T09:45:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/10/29/american-analog-set-trespassers-in-the-stereo-field-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/10/29/american-analog-set-trespassers-in-the-stereo-field-website/">&lt;p&gt;I’m rather thrilled that American Analog set have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amanset.com/&quot;&gt;emerged from a long hibernation with a new album&lt;/a&gt;, that has been ordered. While I’m waiting for it to arrive I’ll reminisce about my past history with them…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/amanset/graphics/trespassers-in-the-stereo-field-2000.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Trespassers in the stereo field (2000)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in the late 1990s I was introduced to American Analog Set by fans on the Galaxie 500 Mailing List - I hunted down all the releases I could - which at the time was three rather great albums and the &lt;em&gt;Bliss Out&lt;/em&gt; EP (that I kind of loved even more). During my scouring of the Internet for information it became clear that Amanset were sorely under-represented in the &lt;em&gt;fan website&lt;/em&gt; stakes… so, as that was &lt;em&gt;my thing&lt;/em&gt; I felt an urge to remedy that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at some point either at the end of 1999 or early in 2000 &lt;em&gt;Trespassers in the stereo field&lt;/em&gt; was born, with the following reason printed proudly on the front page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It just made me sad that there didn’t appear to be a web site dedicated to such a good band - so I built one. My knowledge of American Analog Set has been gleaned from the following sources…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the three albums and one ep I own&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the very VERY limited sleeve notes they contain&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the few reviews and interviews I’ve managed to find on the Internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;blockquote-footer text-right text-muted&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20000606080343/http://www.aald.demon.co.uk:80/amanset/index.html&quot;&gt;Trespassers in the stereo field&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;archived at Wayback Machine (https://web.archive.org/), 6th June 2000&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news page was even less ambitious “if I had any news about the band this is where it would go”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next three or four years the page expanded somewhat, both in content and width, but I never got as fully involved in the world of Amanset as I was (and still am) in the world of Galaxie 500, so the pages became a little neglected - mostly because my time was being used elsewhere, but also because I wasn’t getting a huge amount of engagemnent from other fans - this would have been down to me rather than them! Also, the gaps were being filled elsewhere, other websites started to appear - including an official one - that made it harder for me to commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/amanset/amanset-cassettes.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;American Analog Set cassettes&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2002, I was already considering closing the site but decided that the band were still not that well served on the Internet so I persisted. In July, the band played at 93 Feet East in London and I went along, the only time I saw them live, I met up with a couple of folk who had contacted me through the website, didn’t talk to the band… and that was that. My pal did record the show but I can’t find the recording, I was also sent a recording from another UK date, but can’t find that either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found a couple of casettes I was sent, one with a couple of live shows from 2000; and one with what’s described as “New work 2001” and has the following message inside:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have no -idea- about track titles for these. The cd Kenny gave me had no label or titles or anything. Apart from a slightly different mix of “Only Living Boy Around” this is all new work. Be fore warned : This is, as Kenny puts it, the “rock ‘n’ roll” album. Hee Hee Hee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;blockquote-footer text-right text-muted&quot;&gt;Cassete inlay, 2001&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sadly can’t remember who sent me this - they filled up the other side with synth-pop band &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JbrvGWU_pIg&quot;&gt;Vitesse’s Chelsea 27099 album&lt;/a&gt; which I’ll admit to not having listened to for 20+ years! I currently don’t have a working cassette deck so the Amanset &lt;em&gt;New work&lt;/em&gt; will have to remain a mystery!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 5th November 2004 I declared the site dead, and in March 2005 made one last post pointing users at a new fansite &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20050404222222/http://www.amansetnews.com/&quot;&gt;Amansetnews &lt;em&gt;archived at Wayback Machine (https://web.archive.org&lt;/em&gt;), 4th April 2005&lt;/a&gt; and Amanset’s official site, and finally mothballed the site… and eventually took it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/amanset/graphics/trespassers-in-the-stereo-field-2005.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Trespassers in the stereo field (2005)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit here that I drifted away from the band, and on occasional revisits found them more difficult to love than I had, I think I had changed, the greatness was still there, I just didn’t seem to have the patience to commit to them like I had in those early flushes. I’m older now and the love &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; still there, I think I just needed them to remind me, and maybe this new album has… although it hasn’t arrived yet!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><category term="american analog set" /><summary type="html">I’m rather thrilled that American Analog set have emerged from a long hibernation with a new album, that has been ordered. While I’m waiting for it to arrive I’ll reminisce about my past history with them… Trespassers in the stereo field (2000) At some point in the late 1990s I was introduced to American Analog Set by fans on the Galaxie 500 Mailing List - I hunted down all the releases I could - which at the time was three rather great albums and the Bliss Out EP (that I kind of loved even more). During my scouring of the Internet for information it became clear that Amanset were sorely under-represented in the fan website stakes… so, as that was my thing I felt an urge to remedy that. So at some point either at the end of 1999 or early in 2000 Trespassers in the stereo field was born, with the following reason printed proudly on the front page. It just made me sad that there didn’t appear to be a web site dedicated to such a good band - so I built one. My knowledge of American Analog Set has been gleaned from the following sources… the three albums and one ep I own the very VERY limited sleeve notes they contain the few reviews and interviews I’ve managed to find on the Internet Trespassers in the stereo field archived at Wayback Machine (https://web.archive.org/), 6th June 2000 The news page was even less ambitious “if I had any news about the band this is where it would go”. Over the next three or four years the page expanded somewhat, both in content and width, but I never got as fully involved in the world of Amanset as I was (and still am) in the world of Galaxie 500, so the pages became a little neglected - mostly because my time was being used elsewhere, but also because I wasn’t getting a huge amount of engagemnent from other fans - this would have been down to me rather than them! Also, the gaps were being filled elsewhere, other websites started to appear - including an official one - that made it harder for me to commit. American Analog Set cassettes In May 2002, I was already considering closing the site but decided that the band were still not that well served on the Internet so I persisted. In July, the band played at 93 Feet East in London and I went along, the only time I saw them live, I met up with a couple of folk who had contacted me through the website, didn’t talk to the band… and that was that. My pal did record the show but I can’t find the recording, I was also sent a recording from another UK date, but can’t find that either. I have found a couple of casettes I was sent, one with a couple of live shows from 2000; and one with what’s described as “New work 2001” and has the following message inside: I have no -idea- about track titles for these. The cd Kenny gave me had no label or titles or anything. Apart from a slightly different mix of “Only Living Boy Around” this is all new work. Be fore warned : This is, as Kenny puts it, the “rock ‘n’ roll” album. Hee Hee Hee. Cassete inlay, 2001 I sadly can’t remember who sent me this - they filled up the other side with synth-pop band Vitesse’s Chelsea 27099 album which I’ll admit to not having listened to for 20+ years! I currently don’t have a working cassette deck so the Amanset New work will have to remain a mystery! On the 5th November 2004 I declared the site dead, and in March 2005 made one last post pointing users at a new fansite Amansetnews archived at Wayback Machine (https://web.archive.org), 4th April 2005 and Amanset’s official site, and finally mothballed the site… and eventually took it down. Trespassers in the stereo field (2005) I have to admit here that I drifted away from the band, and on occasional revisits found them more difficult to love than I had, I think I had changed, the greatness was still there, I just didn’t seem to have the patience to commit to them like I had in those early flushes. I’m older now and the love is still there, I think I just needed them to remind me, and maybe this new album has… although it hasn’t arrived yet!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beast from 20,000 Fathoms - Whitley Bay Film Festival</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/27/the-beast-from-20-000-fathoms-whitley-bay-film-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beast from 20,000 Fathoms - Whitley Bay Film Festival" /><published>2023-09-27T13:29:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-27T13:29:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/27/the-beast-from-20-000-fathoms-whitley-bay-film-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/27/the-beast-from-20-000-fathoms-whitley-bay-film-festival/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grange85/53217502308/in/album-72177720311364109/&quot; title=&quot;Heading to a lighthouse to see a film where a lighthouse is destroyed by a dinosaur&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53217502308_757d493555_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heading to a lighthouse to see a film where a lighthouse is destroyed by a dinosaur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I took another trip out to the Lighthouse as part of The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitleybayfilmfestival.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Whitley Bay Film Festival&lt;/a&gt;, this time to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beast_from_20,000_Fathoms&quot;&gt;The Beast From 20,000 Fathoms&lt;/a&gt;. Another well chosen film (and another Harryhausen masterpiece) after last years screening of It Came From Beneath the Sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight’s film was much better attended than last years which was nice to see. The intros and supporting material were overlong and rather dull, and the film didn’t actually start until 45 minutes after the advertised time. Then, ten minutes after it started, the food orders that had been taken at the door arrived and were distributed, which was a bit distracting. Thankfully that happened during the talky bit of the film, and this film isn’t about the talking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the distractions were over we could settle down and watch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhedosaurus&quot;&gt;Rhedosaurus&lt;/a&gt; wreck a lighthouse, rampage through New York, before finally getting its comeuppance among the rollercoasters of Coney Island. Harryhausen wasn’t just a master of stop-motion, he was better than that, he couldn’t just make you believe, he was able to make you emotionally attached to his creatures. So, while Tom and Lee and the military were celebrating its destruction we were mourning the beast who technology had awoken and was now destroying. Genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leads were mostly forgettable, although I do love how fond 50s sci-fi was of women scientists and experts. Cecil Kellaway was the one bright light in amongst the dull humans.
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grange85/53217699740/in/album-72177720311364109/&quot; title=&quot;The Rhedosaurus attacks the lighthouse, while helpless attendees look on&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53217699740_18d544849c_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Rhedosaurus attacks the lighthouse, while helpless attendees look on&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lee Hunter (The Beast from 20,000 Fathoms) - Palaentologist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kay Lawrence (The Creature from the Black Lagoon) - Marine scientist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professor Lesley Joyce (It Came From Beneath the Sea) - Marine biologist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marissa Leonardo (20 Million Miles to Earth) - Medical student&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helen Dobson (Revenge of The Creature) - Marine biologist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dr Ruth Adams (This Island Earth) - Atomic scientist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="film" /><category term="ray harryhausen" /><category term="whitley bay film festival" /><category term="the beast from 20,000 fathoms" /><category term="scifi" /><summary type="html">I took another trip out to the Lighthouse as part of The Whitley Bay Film Festival, this time to see The Beast From 20,000 Fathoms. Another well chosen film (and another Harryhausen masterpiece) after last years screening of It Came From Beneath the Sea. Tonight’s film was much better attended than last years which was nice to see. The intros and supporting material were overlong and rather dull, and the film didn’t actually start until 45 minutes after the advertised time. Then, ten minutes after it started, the food orders that had been taken at the door arrived and were distributed, which was a bit distracting. Thankfully that happened during the talky bit of the film, and this film isn’t about the talking! Once the distractions were over we could settle down and watch the Rhedosaurus wreck a lighthouse, rampage through New York, before finally getting its comeuppance among the rollercoasters of Coney Island. Harryhausen wasn’t just a master of stop-motion, he was better than that, he couldn’t just make you believe, he was able to make you emotionally attached to his creatures. So, while Tom and Lee and the military were celebrating its destruction we were mourning the beast who technology had awoken and was now destroying. Genius. The leads were mostly forgettable, although I do love how fond 50s sci-fi was of women scientists and experts. Cecil Kellaway was the one bright light in amongst the dull humans. Lee Hunter (The Beast from 20,000 Fathoms) - Palaentologist Kay Lawrence (The Creature from the Black Lagoon) - Marine scientist Professor Lesley Joyce (It Came From Beneath the Sea) - Marine biologist Marissa Leonardo (20 Million Miles to Earth) - Medical student Helen Dobson (Revenge of The Creature) - Marine biologist Dr Ruth Adams (This Island Earth) - Atomic scientist</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hitch #33: Spellbound</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/12/hitch-33-spellbound/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hitch #33: Spellbound" /><published>2023-09-12T14:06:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-12T14:06:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/12/hitch-33-spellbound</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/09/12/hitch-33-spellbound/">&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/swirling/hitchcock/hitchcock-spellbound.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Spellbound (1945)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep thinking we’re going to do better and then it’s over nine months before we finally get to the next Hitch film - and what a disappoimntment it turned out to be. Spellbound is not a great film, I’m not sure I ever thought it was but I didn’t realise just how disappointed I’d be this time around. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The staff of Green Manors are the most unprofessional professionals you’re likely to find. They behave like the schoolmistresses at St Trinians, with a contempt for their chosen profession and for their fellow professional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even Constance is shockingly unprofessional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount of blame given to the fact that Constance is a woman is shocking…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… the fact that she seems to accept all this nonsense is also shocking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surrealism! Ffs giant scissors!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gregory Peck … what a block of wood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect it’s because I know the film quite well but Murchison telegraphed his guilt (or Hitch telegraphed Murchison’s guilt) at every opportunity so it didn’t even have the suspense that Hitch is so fond of and famous for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 19 years since I last saw the film and have rated it lower than I did then, although I think I’ve been a bit generous becasue Saboteur is much better and I only gave that a five!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: DVD&lt;br /&gt;
Rating: 4/10 &lt;em&gt;(I did rate it 5/10 but bcs of the Saboteur comment above I’ve downgraded it!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hitchcock Zone: &lt;a href=&quot;https://the.hitchcock.zone/wiki/Spellbound_(1945)&quot;&gt;Spellbound (1945)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;admin&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="hitchcock" /><category term="film" /><summary type="html">Spellbound (1945) I keep thinking we’re going to do better and then it’s over nine months before we finally get to the next Hitch film - and what a disappoimntment it turned out to be. Spellbound is not a great film, I’m not sure I ever thought it was but I didn’t realise just how disappointed I’d be this time around. Here’s why: The staff of Green Manors are the most unprofessional professionals you’re likely to find. They behave like the schoolmistresses at St Trinians, with a contempt for their chosen profession and for their fellow professional. Even Constance is shockingly unprofessional. The amount of blame given to the fact that Constance is a woman is shocking… … the fact that she seems to accept all this nonsense is also shocking. Surrealism! Ffs giant scissors! Gregory Peck … what a block of wood. I suspect it’s because I know the film quite well but Murchison telegraphed his guilt (or Hitch telegraphed Murchison’s guilt) at every opportunity so it didn’t even have the suspense that Hitch is so fond of and famous for. It’s 19 years since I last saw the film and have rated it lower than I did then, although I think I’ve been a bit generous becasue Saboteur is much better and I only gave that a five! Source: DVD Rating: 4/10 (I did rate it 5/10 but bcs of the Saboteur comment above I’ve downgraded it!) Hitchcock Zone: Spellbound (1945)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My May 2023 in film</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/02/my-may-2023-in-film/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My May 2023 in film" /><published>2023-06-02T17:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-06-02T17:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/02/my-may-2023-in-film</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/02/my-may-2023-in-film/">&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/images/my-may-2023-in-film.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My May in Film&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Films watched: 34&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rated before: 10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average score: 5.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the big screen: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Silent films: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non English language films: 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films-watched-by-decade&quot;&gt;Films watched by decade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1920s: 1 (watched) / 8.00 (average rating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1930s: 0 / n/a&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1940s: 7 / 6.14&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1950s: 6 / 6.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1960s: 5 / 4.80&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1970s: 1 / 5.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1980s: 2 / 4.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1990s: 4 / 5.75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2000s: 2 / 4.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2010s: 3 / 4.33&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2020s: 3 / 6.33&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;highest-rated-films&quot;&gt;Highest rated films&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Casablanca (Michael Curtiz, 1942)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Expectations (David Lean, 1946)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="film" /><category term="stats" /><summary type="html">Quick summary and stats about the films I watched in May 2023. #Music #Cinema #Film #Cinemastodon</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My May 2023 in music</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/01/my-may-2023-in-music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My May 2023 in music" /><published>2023-06-01T11:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-06-01T11:26:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/01/my-may-2023-in-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/06/01/my-may-2023-in-music/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;tracks-scrobbled-700&quot;&gt;Tracks scrobbled: 700&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-artists&quot;&gt;Top artists:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Primitives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haiku Salut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stan Tracey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helen and the Horns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dean Wareham&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motorhead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Star&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paula Frazer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All Girl Summer Fun Band&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barry Gray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-albums&quot;&gt;Top albums&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;figure w-100&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R1Q1eUQfNsg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/R1Q1eUQfNsg/sddefault.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid opacity-3h4 mx-auto&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-right&quot;&gt;
    The Primitives - Way Behind Me (Wogan 1988)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Primitives - Lovely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haiku Salut - The General&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stan Tracey - Jazz Britannica, Vol 7&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Footsteps at My Door: BBC Sessions and More - Helen and the Horns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motorhead - Iron Fist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gigs-attended-1&quot;&gt;Gigs attended: 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grange85/52932133520/in/album-72177720308621992/&quot; title=&quot;McCookerybook &amp;amp; Rotifer at The Whitley Bay Carnival&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52932133520_8bd031bb1e_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;McCookerybook &amp;amp; Rotifer at The Whitley Bay Carnival&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCookerybook &amp;amp; Rotifer - Whitley Bay Carnival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="music" /><category term="stats" /><summary type="html">Quick summary and stats about the music I listened to in May 2023. #Music #LastFM #Listening #NowPlaying</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My April 2023 in film</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/02/my-april-2023-in-film/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My April 2023 in film" /><published>2023-05-02T19:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-02T19:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/02/my-april-2023-in-film</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/02/my-april-2023-in-film/">&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.grange85.co.uk/images/2023-04-my-april-in-film.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My April in Film&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Films watched: 43&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rated before: 12&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average score: 5.95/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the big screen: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Silent films: 0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non English language films: 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films-watched-by-decade&quot;&gt;Films watched by decade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1930s: 7 (watched) / 5.71 (average rating)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1940s: 8 / 6.38&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1950s: 6 / 5.83&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1960s: 7 / 5.57&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1970s: 4 / 5.75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1980s: 2 / 6.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1990s: 3 / 3.67&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2000s: 4 / 7.25&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2010s: 0 / n/a&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2020s: 2 / 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;highest-rated-films&quot;&gt;Highest rated films&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.naomivision.com/never-be-a-punching-bag-for-nobody&quot;&gt;Never Be a Punching Bag for Nobody&lt;/a&gt; (Naomi Yang, 2023) - 9&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amélie (Jean-Pierre Jeunet, 2001) - 9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.fullofwishes.co.uk/03-damon_and_naomi/pictures/never-be-a-punching-bag-poster.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Never Be a Punching Bag for Nobody&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="film" /><category term="stats" /><summary type="html">Quick summary and stats about the films I watched in April 2023. #Music #Cinema #Film #Cinemastodon</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My April 2023 in music</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/01/my-april-2023-in-music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My April 2023 in music" /><published>2023-05-01T11:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-01T11:26:00+01:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/01/my-april-2023-in-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4050/swirling/2023/05/01/my-april-2023-in-music/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/35255697@N03/4437612786/in/photolist-2mSsLGK-2mSj2PP-2mSsLH1-7L8VFh-2najDeR-L4bf3N-hBMQX-QuFygk-2eg2k3k-6pvHxD-sfF98z-4u6JRn/&quot; title=&quot;Mischa Auer, Deanna Durbin and Adolphe Menjou&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4044/4437612786_7bc00b6cf6_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mischa Auer, Deanna Durbin and Adolphe Menjou&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tracks-scrobbled-700&quot;&gt;Tracks scrobbled: 700&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-artists&quot;&gt;Top artists:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marc Bolan &amp;amp; T.Rex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deanna Durbin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naomi Yang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spencer Cullum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nina Nastasia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Monkees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Souther Still&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Damon &amp;amp; Naomi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cindy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lorelle Meets The Obsolete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-albums&quot;&gt;Top albums&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;figure w-100&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y-pKYc6mYdw&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/Y-pKYc6mYdw/sddefault.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid opacity-3h4 mx-auto&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-right&quot;&gt;
    T.Rex - Baby Strange (Wembley 1972)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Born to Boogie (Live at Wembley 1972) - Marc Bolan &amp;amp; T.Rex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music from Films - Deanna Durbin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Best of The Monkees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 Hits of Deanna Durbin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never Be a Punching Bag for Nobody - Naomi Yang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gigs-attended-3&quot;&gt;Gigs attended: 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grange85/52805550554/in/datetaken-public/&quot; title=&quot;The Cluny 2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52805550554_ba06c159ce_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Cluny 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nina Nastasia - The Cluny 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;J. Zunz - The Lubber Fiend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cindy - The Cumberland Arms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Andy&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;andy@grange85.co.uk&quot;}</name><email>andy@grange85.co.uk</email></author><category term="music" /><category term="stats" /><summary type="html">Quick summary and stats about the music I listened to in April 2023. #Music #LastFM #Listening #NowPlaying</summary></entry></feed>